PABLO MANRESA NEBOT

Junior Computer Engineer with a background in Machine Learning engineering/researcher or Data Science. Interested in Autoencoders and generative deep learning algorithms. I also am interested in meta-learning and in heuristic algorithms in order to solve problems.

CONTACT

pablo.96.almo@gmail.com

+34 666361514

Almoradí, Alicante (Spain)

@bitblayde

in Pablo Manresa

SKILLS

Programming languages

Python 5 years
R 2 years
Bash 3 years
C++ 4 years
LaTeX & Markdown 3 years
SQL 1 year

Algorithms

Graphs 2 years
Metaheuristics 2 years
Exacts 3 years

Operating Systems

Linux 7 years (Arch Linux, CentOS, Ubuntu...) Windows 7 years

Software & herramientas

Visualization 4 years
(matplotlib, seaborn, plotly)
Data analysis 4 years
(numpy, scipy, pandas, Dplyr, STL)
Machine Learning 4 years
(sklearn, MASS, CARET, E1071, ...)
Deep Learning 4 years

(tensorflow, keras, Pytorch)

Computer Vision 4 years

(OpenCV, skimage, PIL, torchvision, nibabel)

bei)

Math tools 2 years

(SymPy, Geogebra, wxMaxima, SciPy)

Languages

English - Professional Spanish - Native



INFORMATION

Machine and Deep Learning background focused mainly on supervised learning. In addition, I have worked with computer vision algorithms and image processing. I enjoy programming with C and C++ during my spare time.

EXPERIENCE

2019-2021

♀ Freelancer.

During this period I worked on several community and personal projects. Most of them were focused on Machine Learning, Data Science and Computer Vision tasks.

🗯 2021 - Present

♦ Machine Learning Researcher at the university of Granada.

During this work, I have been revisiting the PAC theory as well as the Bayesian theory for implementing PAC upper bounds. Besides, I have been exploring the Machine Learning theory as well as Gaussian Processes. The goal was to implement upper bounds in order to compute the error rate of statistical classifiers in a statistical agnostic mapping tool.

In this project I have worked with Python, Tensorflow, GPy as well as the main data science tools.

EDUCATION

Specialized in Artificial Intelligence.

2021 - 2022♥ University of Alicante, AlicanteMSc in Data Science and

Machine Learning

Score 9/10.

2022 -

• University of Alicante, Alicante

PhD: Deep Learning and Computer Vision

ACHIEVEMENTS

- ₱ IEEE Publication of: Estimating the Severity of Alzheimer's Disease Using Convolutional Neural Networks and Magnetic Resonance Imaging Data at 2020 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium and Medical Imaging Conference (NSS/MIC).
- Finalist of FacePhi Challenge 2022. Which consisted of solving a business biometry problem with teams of 3 people. However, I got the second position participating on my own. My solution: https://github.com/bitblayde/FacePhi_Challenge_2022.

PROJECTS

Alzheimer detection: This was the project I presented during my bachelor thesis. Specifically, I implemented convolutional neural networks for discriminative tasks and another one for measuring the disease phase, using 3D volumetric images as inputs. The tools I used were Python, Keras and Nibabel.

Meta-learning: During my MSc thesis, I reviewed the state of the art for meta-learning and I implemented some of those algorithms for solving a few-shot learning task with Pytorch.

Cifar-10 models: For learning purposes, I read some papers about the most important convolutional architectures and I decided to implement them on my own. Python and Pytorch were the tools I used. https://github.com/bitblayde/Pytorch_CNN_cifar10

Nonlinear Optimization: Through this project, I implemented several optimization algorithms to optimize problems with mathematical functions and datasets. Specifically, optimization algorithms that make use of derivatives such as Gradient Descent, SGD, Newton... In addition, I implemented mathematical methods for choosing a learning rate that satisfies Wolfe and Armijo conditions. I used Python. https://github.com/bitblayde/Non-linear-Optimization

Statistical-Learning: While I was reading the book "An Introduction to Statistical Learning: With Applications in R" I proposed my own solutions to the exercises I found more challenging. For this project I have used the R language. https://github.com/bitblayde/Statistical-Learning

NLP: I made 2 relevant projects using NLP techniques, the first one consisted of a GRU network to detect Reber language. On the other hand I implemented 3 models for generating text in a Shakespearean way, using stateless and stateful RNN and a bidirectional GRU. I used Python, Tensorflow and Keras. https://github.com/bitblayde/Machine-and-Deep-learning-projects/tree/main/NLP

Other: Other relevant projects I did, were Computer vision algorithms for detecting contours or implementing my own filters. Afterwards, I implemented an autoencoder for an image segmentation task. Regarding data mining I also implemented notebooks in a Kaggle format with tabular data, using tools like Sklearn, pandas, Plotly, Seaborn, Tensorflow and so on. https://github.com/bitblayde/Data-mining, https://github.com/bitblayde/Machine-and-Deep-learning-projects.